<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>My Portfolio - Cristian Gonzaga</title>
        <link>http://example.org/en/</link>
        <description>My cool site. Cristian Gonzaga López</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>cristiangl2430@gmail.com (Cristian Gonzaga López)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>cristiangl2430@gmail.com (Cristian Gonzaga López)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 22:16:33 -0500</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="http://example.org/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>Databases for Data Scientists</title>
    <link>http://example.org/en/posts/databases-for-data-scientists/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 22:16:33 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Cristian Gonzaga</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/en/posts/databases-for-data-scientists/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The Databases for Data Scientists course, offered by University of Colorado Boulder and taught by Alan Paradise, teaches about database design, database software fundamentals, and how to use the Structured Query Language (SQL) to work with databases. Concludes with an overview of future trends in databases, including non-relational databases (NoSQL) and Big Data. Therefore, upon completion of this specialization, one is ready to design and create efficient and effective relational databases, fill them with data, and work with them using SQL.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Advanced Topics and Future Trends in Database Technologies</title>
    <link>http://example.org/en/posts/advanced-topics_future-trends_database-technologies/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 14:46:39 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Cristian Gonzaga</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/en/posts/advanced-topics_future-trends_database-technologies/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The Advanced Topics and Future Trends in Database Technologies course, offered by University of Colorado Boulder and taught by Di Wu and Alan Paradise, teaches some of the more in-depth and advanced areas of database technologies, followed by a look at the future of database software and where the industry is heading.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Business Metrics for Data-Driven Companies</title>
    <link>http://example.org/en/posts/business-metrics_data-driven-companies/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 17:21:57 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Cristian Gonzaga</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/en/posts/business-metrics_data-driven-companies/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The Business Metrics for Data-Driven Companies course, offered by Duke University and taught by Daniel Egger, are provided how to use data analytics to make any company more competitive and more profitable, recognizing the most critical business metrics and distinguish them from mere data.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The Structured Query Language (SQL)</title>
    <link>http://example.org/en/posts/structured-query-language/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 15:39:15 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Cristian Gonzaga</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/en/posts/structured-query-language/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The Structured Query Language (SQL) course, offered by University of Colorado Boulder and taught by Alan Paradise, reviews the origins of the language and its conceptual foundations. But primarily, focus on learning all the standard SQL commands, their syntax, and how to use these commands to conduct analysis of the data within a relational database. Finally, includes the DDL ('Data Definition Language') and DML ('Data Manipulation Language') commands necessary to create and maintain database objects.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Relational Database Design</title>
    <link>http://example.org/en/posts/relational-database-design/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 15:17:43 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Cristian Gonzaga</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/en/posts/relational-database-design/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The Relational Database Design course, offered by University of Colorado Boulder and taught by Di Wu, provides a step-by-step guidance to start from a raw idea to an implementable relational database.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Share your Knowledge</title>
    <link>http://example.org/en/posts/comparte-tu-conocimiento/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 20:43:13 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Cristian Gonzaga</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/en/posts/comparte-tu-conocimiento/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In Mexico, there is a high dropout rate at the high school level. In order to prepare students to have a better job, the project Comparte tu Conocimiento of the H. Ayuntamiento de Atizapán de Zaragoza - Dirección de Educación seeks to provide counseling in different subjects of open high school to adults and young people of the municipality. ]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How Things Work: An Introduction to Physics</title>
    <link>http://example.org/en/posts/how-things-work_an-introduction-physics/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 21:22:38 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Cristian Gonzaga</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/en/posts/how-things-work_an-introduction-physics/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The course How Things Work: An Introduction to Physics, offered by University of Virginia and taught by Louis A. Bloomfield, provides an accessible introduction to physics employing everyday objects to explain the most essential physics concepts of day-to-day life.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Data Science Ethics</title>
    <link>http://example.org/en/posts/data-science-ethics/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 21:41:22 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Cristian Gonzaga</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/en/posts/data-science-ethics/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This course provides a broader impact of the data science field on modern society and the principles of fairness, accountability and transparency. In addition, examines the ethical and privacy implications of collecting and managing big data. Finally, it emphasized who owns data, how do we value privacy, how to receive informed consent and what it means to be fair.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Coppel Route Optimization</title>
    <link>http://example.org/en/posts/optimizacion-de-rutas-coppel/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 22:19:48 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Cristian Gonzaga</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/en/posts/optimizacion-de-rutas-coppel/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[With the accelerated growth of e-commerce in recent years, it has become critical for companies to adapt to the new landscape. It is becoming increasingly common to order products online, and the companies must find the right logistics solutions to ensure that their products reach their customers. Efficiency and optimization are key to sucess, as companies seek to minimize distribution costs and delivery times while meeting customer expectations. These logistics strategies involve finding optimal routes, something that can be studied from problems such as the Traveling Salesman Problem and the Capacitated Vehicle Routing Problem (CVRP), which are applications of Linear Programming. This paper applies the above concepts, as well as Machine Learning algorithms, to solve a routing problem for the company Grupo Coppel, from one of its distribution centers in Azcapotzalco, Mexico City.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>QS World Ranking Analysis</title>
    <link>http://example.org/en/posts/qs_world-ranking/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 21:55:35 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Cristian Gonzaga</author>
    <guid>http://example.org/en/posts/qs_world-ranking/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[University rankings are lists that evaluate universities around the world based on different metrics. For prospective students, university rankings may seem like a simple way to assess the quality of an institution, shortlist options and make decisions. While for universities, rankings can be a planning tool, which allows them to define strategies and objectives to improve their reputation and therefore student attraction.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
